regenerative design is the art and
science of enabling people in place to
create healthy whole resilient socio
ecological systems through working on
collaborative abundance rather than
competitive scarcity it is about working
with the latent potential in each place
to work towards increased health
wholeness and resilience working with
the people on creating elegant solutions
carefully adapted to the bio cultural
uniqueness of the spaces they inhabit it
is predominantly local and regional in
the sense that it works with both the
regional and local culture and the
limits and opportunities of regional and
local ecosystems it tries to meet the
essential needs of local populations by
creating vibrant regenerative business
ecologies that link businesses in a
collaborative endeavor to create through
local production or regional production
for regional consumption the fundamental
needs of the local population but it
goes beyond that
regenerative development in its most
audacious is about redesigning the human
presence on earth from being
predominantly destructive and
exploitative to being by and large
regenerative both socially ecologically
and economically this can be done
through global collaboration and careful
local and regional application we can
share knowledge from region to region we
need to understand that building a
regenerative civilization is about
helping everybody in their place to do
their bit to create regenerative
cultures that are carefully adapted to
the bio cultural uniqueness of the
places
in habit so regenerative development is
not something done by specialists it is
something that we need to bring into
schools into businesses into public
authorities everywhere
in order to find a whole system's design
approach to achieving agenda 2030
implementing the sustainable development
goals finding a transformative response
to climate change one example being the
regenerative development to reverse
climate change initiative of the
Commonwealth and we are currently seeing
a global revolution of the regeneration
rising of people working in agriculture
in economics in city design and local
community design on regenerative
solutions and we can learn from each
other always remembering that each of
those solutions has to be unique to the
place and it has to come out of that
place in work with the people of that
place in doing so we will be able to
create a world that is richer and more
abundant with healthier soils healthier
ecosystems and with a protection of
biodiversity and a strategy to not just
combat climate changes as often it is
often called but to actually go beyond
it to make an opportunity out of this
global situation and bring carbon home
bring it back into the soil bring it
back into biomaterials bring it back
into standing forests into healthy
analog forests that provide the basis of
our new circularly focused biomaterials
economies and it is also about healing
the relationship between humanity and
nature understanding that we are
fundamentally part of nature and
depending on it taking a book out of the
pages from biomimicry and understanding
that as human beings we have the
capacity to create conditions conducive
to life that we can create richer and
more abundant futures if we shift from a
mindset that has us focused on
native advantage and move towards a
mindset that shows us that we can create
collaborative abundance not just for all
of humanity but for the community of
life as a whole that we can create a
healthier and more productive planet so
I hope you join the regeneration I'm
excited about it
it's happening it's our chance to
respond to the converging crisis with a
transformative innovation response